Welcome to the other section. So, in this section we are going to learn about how anti-vera
software and EDRs will work. So, EDR means the end point detection and response. So,
let me learn about how this kind of a different engine will work ok. So, before directly
jumping into the bypassing anti-vera software, we need to understand how the how the
difference I, it is difference engines will work ok. So, let I will open my note pad, I will
reduce the theory part here, I will explain most of the things in practical. So, if you
come to the anti-vera engine. So, you can you can have 3 engines ok, not 3, 4 engines, let
we will speak about the static dynamic heuristic and unpacker. So, we are going to talk
about this 3 engines, I will give some overall brief of the unpacker ok. So, let us first
talk about the static engine. So, before that I will jump into my anti-vera software and
see how it was, how it detect, how it will detect a threat ok. So, let I will jump to
my bit differenter. So, you can you can see I think there is one protection was disabled.
So, we are protection. So, if I enable the protection my anti-vera is showing a green
check mode right. So, my anti-vera system is active to scan the threat ok. So, let I will
give some job to my anti-vera software and I will see what what happened in the background.
So, let me let let download a mimic art file from a website that we will see what happening
in the background. So, if I click on the download my I cannot see the file of download
because AC the my bit differenter showing all enter detector. So, let us click on more details
and we will see what happening in the background.
Yeah, you can see we block the dangerous page for your protection right. So, how it how it
blocked ok. So, let I will take this URL and I will put it in virus total. Let us see
how this URL was blocked. So, EX, EX. So, here you can find some of the anti-vera
vendors flagged this flag this pages malicious right you can see the bit differenter flagged
this pages malware. So, now you can understand why this page was blocked ok. So, let I will
open my presentation here you can see the static signature database. So, this is the static
engine. So, here you can you have some of the executable DLL dogs it will go to the comparing
ok. So, it will take the executable hash and compare it with the signature database.
So, this is the signature database it contains all the malicious hash hash value. So, we
will call that as a signatures it is a pattern it will compare that executable hash with
the database if the hash matches it will it will disable desired whether the file was
been in or a malicious ok. So, let us say your you are going to build one of the new malware
and that malware will not be present in the signature database. So, you can easily bypass
the a v engine right because your signature will not be present in the database ok. So,
if the anti-vera software using the using only the static engine you can easily bypass
the anti-vera software by creating a new malware ok. But, wait that the attacker will
decide this kind of thing. So, easily they will they will change some of the functions
instead they are execute malware malicious program and they will create a new new malware
right. So, the a v engine is decided a new engine to to different against this kind of
thread ok. So, this is a static engine and it was a just good because it detected from a
signature in the same scenario this was happened ok. I just to go into the go into the
mini cat's .exe URL and my my a bit different anti-vera software is detected there are
pages or malicious right. So, here you can find it flag does a malware ok. So, the same thing
your this page was detected as a malicious page right. So, this is how the anti-vera
programs will work in the background ok. Let us download let us turn off the protections
and we will check what what happened in the background if I download the mini cat file. So,
you can see the mini cat file was ready to download, but it showing its need permission
right and if I if I if I move to the download. So, you can see it was failed in sufficient
permission let let let let move to the a bit different page and we will check what
happening inside the background ok. So, you can see some of the infected term files get
cleared be a be a because when I when I click on the download my my browser application
will will create a term file inside that folder ok. So, for example, the mini cat is 64
be file file. So, if you want to download that file. So, my my my my my browser application
will create a term file inside the inside the directory and it will download download the
mini cat ok. So, whenever the download was completed the term file get change changed into
the mini cat start EXO ok. So, this why the term file get detected and cleaned up right.
So, in my previous in my previous things. So, here infected file detector. So, here you
can find the cat fails also get cleared because I downloaded the mini cats I tried to download
the mini cats yesterday. So, but but but it it caused the same thing what happening
in today ok. So, you can see some catch files also get detected and cleared because this
URL I downloaded in the in this URL right this URL will be saved in the catch file the
Chrome catch file. So, that it will get detected and removed ok. So, think how smart
our antivirus after this right. So, if you if you see the attack timeline. So, let
I will bring out bring out bring the attack timeline. So, here you can find the explorer
dot EXO opened a chrome dot EXO and the chrome dot EXO moved to the on of the URL and
again the threat was sorry the chrome dot EXO the catch file get detected as a threat
detector and you can see the melee malware its malicious software design to damage our
your devices and it was described by the bit different or let see this timeline what what
happened yeah. Now, also some catch files get cleared right because I visited the URL and
tried to download the mini cat site. So, this is how your antivirus after will will work
and this this is what the static detection ok. So, the static detection your signature
files there is a signature database and once your hash matched with the signature database
it will detect their file file as malicious ok. If it was not if the hash value was not
present inside the signature database the antivirus after will allow that software to execute
inside the system ok if it was only using the static engine. So, let us talk about the
next engine dynamic engine. So, if you see the dynamic engine so, it was a simple diagram
I just put in the slide ok. So, the same thing the files will go under the APA monitoring
and sandboxing ok what is APA monitoring let us discuss about the APA monitoring ok. So,
what is APA I already told what is APA and how APA work and what is the purpose of the APA
ok and I will I showed some of the malicious APA right. So, if you see the process injection
attack we are using we are using three common APA ok. So, one is virtual a log of and another
one is right proc memory of and another one is create remotely of we are using three
APAs for a process injection attack. Let I will go to my Chrome and let I will redirect
one of the one of the one of the site called mal APA let us see what what what is inside
the mal APA. So, if you see the website it will show all the malicious APA that was used
by the threat attackers ok. So, if you see the injection based attack you can find you can
find the virtual a log of function I discuss right virtual a log e x of function. So,
you can see it is often used to be malware to allocate a memory inside the process right
memory inside a remote process as part of process injection ok it was used for a process injection
we will we will program this in this in the routine operation section how to program
a process injection. And we are going to see that in a practical way how to take a
remote shell using the process injection ok. So, this virtual a log and virtual a log
of function was in the mal APA. So, this was a common APA that was abused by the threat
attackers to create their malicious software right. So, if you if you if you go to the other
part let sets for their right control F right. So, you can see the right process memory
of it will it will copy the payload into the target memory this was the main functionality
of the APA right process memory of. So, this memory the this APA function is based on
the kernel 32 dot DLL library. So, let us go to the create remote thread of APA remote
yeah. You can see the create remote thread of APA is used to create a thread we already
saw what is thread. So, thread is an execution object of a program. So, it will create
a remote thread ok. So, it it is also based on a kernel kernel 32 dot DLL library. And
it was basically used for a injection attack we are we are going to see this kind of
DLLs in our practical section or a team operation. So, in the dynamic engine ok in the dynamic
engine or your anti-virus software will monitor monitor the APA ok. So, for example, which
are the APAs are used if it was if it comes under malicious APAs are not ok. Plus it it will
use the sandboxing ok it will execute the program inside the sandbox environment. So,
sandbox environment is like like a virtual machine it will it will create the own virtual
machine and it will execute the malicious program and it will check it what behavior
it was creating ok. What was the behavior of the executable program. So, by that you
can understand by that the AV engine will understand whether this application was malicious
or a rename ok. So, this is the dynamic engine ok. Let me so, threat actor will abuse
this this dynamic engine easily ok. So, they will they will use some encoding methods
or encryption method to hide the APA monitoring to bypass the dynamic engine ok. So, then
the AV the AV engines think in a smart way to create another engine called the shear
is taking engine ok. So, the heuristic engine is like the heuristic engine have a predefined
roles ok. For example, let I will move to my task manager. So, any of the programming
programs. So, let us see any any of the third party program or a system internal. So, if
you try to access a l-s as it will a malicious right. So, let I will create a malicious
here ok. So, here you can see the l-s program if I create a dump file. So, this is a malicious
behavior right. So, you can see this infection in process right. This is the heuristic engine.
So, any third party program or a Windows internals if it was accessing l-s as memory. So,
l-s as it is basically for a for a log interrelated stuff. So, ok my my V different are
cleared everything ok. It deleted the task manager completely no problem I will ok. We cannot
find the program in a specific path ok. I will install the task manager no problem ok.
So, in any programs here it will access a l-s as memory it will be a malicious right. So,
l-s as is responsible for log interrelated things. So, the log interrelated credentials
will be stored inside the l-s as program. So, if any process accessing the l-s as program.
So, it was a it was a malicious right. So, it has some predefined rules like any of the program
accessed l-s as see my task manager is a Windows Windows internals, but it did not care about
that program right. It directly deleted because that was a rule inside the heuristic engine
ok. Any of the program access tells us just block it just try the program ok. So, this
is the rule they will write in the database and if the rule satisfied it will it will
block that ok. So, it will decide the malicious R B name. Now, in our scenario it deleted
it removed the task manager from my machine. So, the sad part let ok. So, no problem I
will I will retrieve it ok. So, yes we will we will see the attack timeline ok application
task manager has access has been detected potentially malicious and application path command
line parameter slash 4 ok. So, it was behavior ok. So, it was it was detector as a suspicious
behavior already is said if it if there is any suspicious behavior inside a program it will
detect and delete that program ok. So, let us let us jump on to the next next one
we have an unpacker right. So, some some time the malware executable with comes with a
packer like it will use the obfuscation encryption and this kind of methods to bypass
the AV engine. So, your antivirus software have a proper unpacker. So, if you if your
antivirus software did not have that unpacker engine. So, you can easily the threat
factor can easily bypass the antivirus software we are not going to discuss more about this
because I I I I took out one of the section and I will I will upload the video in the
last section in the knowledge base section called bypassing ADR and EVs sorry bypass
AV and EDRs we you can you can watch section to learn more about bypassing the antivirus
later things ok. So, in that section I discussed about the who whoking and hooking hallows
gate and all. So, you can you can if you are really interested in bypassing antivirus
software you can watch watch a video that will be very helpful when you are when you are
doing such things ok. There are some end of our videos and you can you can find many things
you there was a I will I will prefer you have to complete all the section first and you
can go for that section ok. Don't jump into the section directly because you won't get
any of things because that was little bit advanced section. So, my advice is to complete
all the section first routine operations and all then jump on to the bypassing ADR ok
knowledge base section ok. So, in that section I discussed lot of things like incident response
and bypassing these ADRs and AV engines ok with the more advanced techniques.
So, let us API is ok let us jump on to the protection system ok what are the protection
system. So, let us discuss about the protection system what are the protection system currently
we have we have an EDR. So, let us think about what is EDR ok. So, EDR is a end point detection
and response. So, in this slide you can see the EDR one of the EDR name does code strike
file count it I took this image from from one of the website. So, this is the concierge
this is the geo interface of the EDR. So, EDR is basically a end point detection and
response system it will it will protect the user from advanced persistent threats ATP and
malware through the real time response ok through the real time response let I will
practically explain what I see what is EDR ok. So, you can see in the most recent detection
so, this is a host ID and if you if you click on the view details it will it will show
the details ok. So, it is basically it is basically the anti the EDR vendor will install
your sensor inside the target machine ok it they will install some EDR sensor in the target
machine that sensor will monitor the behavior and the activity of the machine ok and it
will send all the logs to the EDR EDR vendors ok. For example, if you are if you are using
a code strike file can EDR the code strike file can fail can company will install some
sensor inside your target machine and that sensor will monitor your machine and it will
send all the logs to the code strike file company and that organization that team will monitor
what happening inside your machine ok. So, for example, in this scenario there is a host
ID this is a host name and there is a tactics command and control via remote ok see to see
was detected if they click on the view details it will it will give the details ok it
this is how EDR will look like if you go to the next slide. So, you can see you can query
the EDR ok you can query the EDRs and you can see the particular data for example, if you
want to if you want the running process for a machine you can query if you want a persistence
or registry run key for a machine you can use a query to see all the things ok.
Also, it have one of the one of advanced mechanism called a C process tree ok it will show
the process tree 1 by 1 what happened in the machine ok. We already discussed in the process
chain it will show the data like that ok. It the outlook spawn the data minver.exe
maybe the user opened some open macro enable document or malicious document from the outlook
it spawned the vendor minver.exe and minver.exe spawn PowerShell.exe absolutely
there is a macro enable document. So, it opened a PowerShell.exe and PowerShell.exe is
doing some malicious stuff ok right. So, here you can see the in right hand side you can
see the host name and all the details if the EDR will show like that ok. For example,
if you are taking some of the other EDR like carbon black or Microsoft advanced detection
defender. So, that EDR have a separate a chart for this ok it is separate graphical
view representation ok. So, in I will go to the next slide. So, here you can see the
PowerShell command line you can see the command line also what command get executed execute
and save the machine ok. So, this is how the EDR will operate ok it will collect the logs
from the target machine ah even machine. So, if your purchase the EDR license it will collect
all the logs from your machine and it will send that logs to the EDR vendors who is
managing your EDR and that team will monitor your system behavior ok. That was the primary
primary ah responsibility for the team they need to monitor your ah your system behavior
and the activity ok. So, in right hand side you can see the PowerShell right.
So, let us go to the another slide. So, the same thing we have and EDR have one of the
advanced thing the real time response ok. So, you can so, the EDR vendor can query directly
query in said your machine ok. So, in EDR there is a separate option called the live
response if you if you enable to the live response. So, your EDR ah vendors can directly
query into the machine. So, it was very helpful when you are facing EDR of the active
instance. So, if if you are facing any of the active thread. So, at that time so, EDR vendors
can directly jump into your machine by using the command command and control. So, there
is a separate ah tab for a live response. So, they will use their live response and directly
query into a query into a machine. They can easily delete ah killed the service or they
can delete the delete the ah executable ah they can they can do a lot of things ok inside
your machine directly without any without any interactions ok. So, it is basically they
will get to one of the command prompt with the system privilege. So, they can do a lot
of they can do a lot of things ok when if you are facing any active instance. So, that
is called as the real time response we will call it as a live response ok.
So, this is how your EDR will work and we have a firewall. So, firewall is basically ah
a network monitoring system it will it will detect the network based threads. So, for
example, if any of the IP was blacklisted as a cobalt strike it will detect that IP and
it will block the IP ok. So, it will block the IP ok. So, there was a primary responsibility
of the firewall ah it will it will see the network based thread ok. So, blocking the
IP is URLs and all. So, next we have ah IPs and the ideas intrusion prevention and intrusion
detection system it will basically monitor ah monitor your network packets ah like what
are the packets it was receiving if you open a wires arc you can see a lot of packets right.
So, it will it will it will it will investigate that packet and it will monitor ah if there
is any malicious ah malicious executable or malicious behavior inside the process ok sorry
in the inside the packet ok. So, it will monitor the packet network packets and it will
detect that packet ah if it was malicious ok. So, next we have a DLP. So, it is a data loss
prevention. So, it was I already discussed many a ransomware detector ah if it is a ransomware
ah they will use a or clone or some other ah third particular ah for exfiltration right data
exfiltration they will upload the data into the ah DLP data link sites or any other
cloud platform they threat actor will do that ah exfiltration. So, in that time DLP will
ah helpful to prevent that kind of ah exfiltration ok. So, it will prevent the organization
from the data exfiltration these are the some protection ah protection system ah currently
we have in our ah in our world ok. So, we we discussed a few of the things and if you
need to more if you need to learn more about the ah antivirus bypassing EDRs how the
gates will work and how the hooking will work and ah types of ah gates ah this all the things
you can find in the knowledge base section. So, that video was very very useful if you
are really ah ah if you if you really need a ah ah ah different salvation related things ok.
If you if you if you need a ah evading antivirus after that and all ok. So, ah I think I
discussed a lot of things and ah let I will think ah what are the other things to discuss
discuss ah EDRs starting in dynamic engine ok ah LPE EDRs ok yeah I discussed all the things
ah we will we will meet you in the next section ah yeah my study also completed ah we will
discuss in ah next video ah yep bye bye see you in the next video thank you.